# Kia Rahmani Ph.D.

**८** 765-588-8872 **○** kiarahmani Austin, TX

✓ kiar@utexas.edu

kiarahmani.github.io in kia-rahmani

I am a computer scientist with over 10 years of research experience in the industry and academia. I am passionate about designing programming language-based tools to enable more generalizable, interpretable, and reliable machine/robot learning algorithms. I am a highly motivated team player and am always eager to learn new things.

#### **Education**

**Purdue University** 2017 - 2022

Ph.D. in Computer Science

IN, USA

- > Thesis: Symbolic Analysis of Weak Concurrency Semantics in Modern Database Programs
- > Advisors: Suresh Jagannathan & Benjamin Delaware

**Purdue University** 2015 - 2017

M.Sc. in Computer Science

IN, USA

> Selected Courses: Programming Languages, Adv. Topics in Programming Languages, Computer-aided Reasoning, Distributed Database Systems, Verifying Systems At Scale, Formal Methods In Databases, Information Security

### **Sharif University of Technology**

2010 - 2015

B.Sc. in Computer Science

Tehran, IRAN

> Undergraduate Thesis: A Survey on Three-ballot Voting Mechanism: Algorithms and Attacks

# **Work Experience**

Post-doctoral Scientist

#### The University of Texas at Austin

09/2022 - Current

TX, USA

- > Research Focus: Symbolic Methods for Enhancement of Robot Learning from Demonstration and Experience
- > Advisors: Isil Dillig & Joydeep Biswas

**Microsoft Corporation** 06/2020 - 12/2020

Research Intern

WA, USA

- > Project: Program Inference using GPT-3 Large Language Model
- > Supervisors: Sumit Gulwani & Mohammad Raza

**Purdue University** 08/2015 - 08/2022

Graduate Research and Teaching Assistant

IN, USA

# Publications & Patents

## **Program Synthesis for Robot Learning from Demonstrations (arxiv)**

**Under Submission** 

> Noah Patton, Kia Rahmani, Meghana Missula, Joydeep Biswas, Isil Dillig

#### Probabilistic Program Synthesis for Learning from Unlabeled and Noisy Demonstrations (arxiv)

**Under Submission** 

> Jimmy Xin, Linus Zheng, Jiayi Wei, Kia Rahmani, Jarrett Holtz, Isil Dillig, Joydeep Biswas

#### Multi-modal Program Inference (USPTO Application)

US 20230176829A1

> Kia Rahmani, Mohammad Raza, Sumit Gulwani, Vu Le, Daniel Morris, Arjun Radhakrishna, Gustavo Soares, Ashish Tiwari

#### Multi-modal Program Inference: LLMs and Component-based Synthesis (doi)

OOPSLA'21

> Kia Rahmani, Mohammad Raza, Sumit Gulwani, Vu Le, Daniel Morris, Arjun Radhakrishna, Gustavo Soares, Ashish Tiwari

#### Repairing Serializability Bugs in Distributed Database Programs via Automated Schema Refactoring (doi)

PLDI'21

> Kia Rahmani, Kartik Nagar, Benjamin Delaware and Suresh Jagannathan

#### CLOTHO: Directed Test Generation for Weakly Consistent Database Systems (doi)

OOPSLA'19

> Kia Rahmani, Kartik Nagar, Benjamin Delaware and Suresh Jagannathan

## Fine-grained Distributed Consistency Guarantees with Effect Orchestration (doi)

PaPoC'18

> Kia Rahmani, Gowtham Kaki and Suresh Jagannathan

# Kia Rahmani, Ph.D.

Post-doctoral Scientist

**८** 765-588-8872 **♠** kiarahmani ✓ Austin, TX

kiarahmani.github.io in kia-rahmani

✓ kiar@utexas.edu

#### **♥** Skills

**Programming Languages** I have worked on numerous projects written in various programming languages, and I am proficient in C/C++, Java, C#, Python, Haskell, OCaml, etc.

Formal Methods I have a deep knowledge of logical frameworks for specifying computer systems and their properties, which I have utilized in my past research, including temporal logics (such as LTL, CTL, STL, etc.), rely-guarantee reasoning (RG), separation logic (SL), correctness/incorrectness logic, etc.

**Model Checking and Verification** I have acquired extensive experience in reducing a wide range of program analysis and verification problems to SAT and SMT instances. I am proficient in utilizing several prominent tools in this domain, such as Z3, Spin, Dafny, Alloy, Ultimate, SeaHorn, CVC-5, and Coq.

**Databases and Data Management** I have an extensive background in analyzing and implementing distributed data management systems with a wide range of concurrency semantics. I have developed multiple software applications that utilize various off-the-shelf database systems, including MongoDB, Apache Cassandra, Spanner, CosmosDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL, and more. I have also used several libraries for MVC database program design, including Django, Ruby on Rails, and Spring.

Machine Learning I have knowledge of various machine learning algorithms, with a particular focus on deep reinforcement learning. I am familiar with existing frameworks such as PyTorch and OpenAI Gym.

Software Development Git, Docker, Jira, VSCode, Unix

#### **References**

**Isil Dillig** Professor, The University of Texas at Austin, isil@cs.utexas.edu Suresh Jagannthan Samuel D. Conte Professor, Purdue University, suresh@cs.purdue.edu **Sumit Gulwani** Partner Research Manager, Microsoft Corporation, sumitg@microsoft.com Benjamin Delaware Assistant Professor, Purdue University, bendy@purdue.edu Joydeep Biswas Associate Professor, The University of Texas at Austin, joydeepb@cs.utexas.edu